Hi, in this lesson, I will show you how to quickly start with your top compiler.
It means I will show you how to work with some basic features, do a quick overview and
show you some examples, but of course this will be a really short lesson, just that
you have some quick overview, and the more deeper I will dive in the next lesson.
So I will recommend you to finish this course and not stop on this lesson.
So to work with the compiler we need to have at least the thumb project, I will open my
project folder and create a new folder, with name hit half-propilot, you can name whatever
you want, and now we can click on open folder from sidebar, or if you don't have a sidebar
you can click on file, open folder, and now you can choose your project folder, and click
open, okay, you can close the welcome screen, and now to work with scopilot we need to create
at least one file to be able to see the suggestions, I will name it calculator.js,
So when you provide a name for a file, it's a context for compiler, you know what
is file is about, and can do more relevant suggestions when we type something.
So first thing I will show you how works chart completions, when you start typing something,
compiler to be able to predict what you want to implement, and we will do the completions
for you.
I will type class, because I want to implement calculator class, and you see a pilot do
suggestion for us.
We have constructor with initial value, we have method to add, subtract, multiply and
divide, and also method to clear.
You see the implementation is good yet, and if I like it we can accept it.
We have few options how we can accept it, we can click on a blue, a square with the check
mark, or we can also click on go.set or reject option, also we can use some shortcuts,
if you want to accept we can use stop or reject we want to use, if you want to reject
we use escape, I will use stop to accept this suggestion, okay, now imagine we want to implement
something new and I will show you how to work with inline suggestion, so let's add something
of the divide methods.
You see after we move our cursor, a compiler automatically suggests some functionality
which we think might be useful for us, if not we can just ignore it.
And also the suggestions will work, they should be enabled, so when you hover on this
compiled icon here you need to set all the check marks, and then the suggestions will
work for you, okay, now let's implement a secure tab method, I will click common dot
i, command dot i, this is a combination for mark, for windows i suppose you need to use
control plus i, and now we click this combination and I will ask at a secure tab method,
a secure tab method is just to take a square root, and after I ask you see the suggestion
from compiler, you see check the number is not negative, otherwise it can't do an operation
and then it use mess library and the secure tab method, do you implement it, okay, we
can click accept if I like it, so and now let's do some other operation and we will do
it through the chart, this icon at the top if you click on it it will show a chart of
compile it, you see a lot of controls here, we will go through them in later on lessons,
and now let's ask how to implement fine change method or negate method, it's for example
when you want to make the positive number negative and the negative number opposite the
positive, how to implement negate method, you see it used, the reference, the reference
is the file, the context where we work in, and it also at some explanation for us, show
the code example, how it can be implemented in our file, or we just not say the implement
negate function like this, it see what is implementation of our class and where he can
put it, so it's really smart, and you see the negate method, this is how it works, and
to accept it weak of course can probably paste it manually, but this is not the way how we
should do it, so we can hover on the first icon, it means apply, after we click on it,
the compiler automatically edit and we can just click keep or undo if you don't like it,
we just click keep, save it, okay this is how a chart works, now we want to show you also
some smart actions and how to fix, how to do quick fixes with your code, let's imagine
we have some broken functionality for a subtraction, you see after I broke the code that
automatically suggests to fix it, so we just ignore it, don't want to do it like clip,
I click escape button, so it disappears, and now we can highlight the code and click comment
I, use slash, and choose the fix command, this is the smart actions, we will go through
them in separate lesson, now we just use the fix, so we provided the file, some area, so
compiled understands the context, and he provides an explanation for us why it doesn't work
and how to fix it, and he can't click just accept, does have this fix, so you see it did
the fix for us, okay, now you know how to basically work with it up a pilot, but it's
only the small percent of features we can use, and the next lesson I will do a deeper
dive and show you more, also a recommendation, please don't ask a pilot to build a whole
project in Visual Studio Code or any other data, because because one can't read your
thoughts, so you have your vision of project, the pilot don't read your thoughts, so you
need to provide really big problem to explain everything, how you want to implement, and
in one shot it doesn't work normally, because it won't be ideal, so when you write something
it's still your responsibility for compiler generates, so you always need to check and correct
the answer if it's needed, so better ask it to build a functionality step-by-step like
one function like one file, one component, so but not the whole project, okay, see you
in the next lesson.